<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on </title>
    <link>https://blog.ritikahotwani.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2024 | Ritika Hotwani</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 13:28:26 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.ritikahotwani.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Introduction</title>
      <link>https://blog.ritikahotwani.com/posts/machine-learning-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 13:28:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.ritikahotwani.com/posts/machine-learning-introduction/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionMachine learning is a fascinating field at the intersection of computer science and statistics, where computers are trained to learn from data and make decisions.&#xA;In this introductory blog, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the basics of machine learning, its differences from deep learning and artificial intelligence, essential programming languages and libraries, and dive into some fundamental concepts and models.&#xA;What is Machine Learning( ML )Machine learning is a subset of artificial intelligence that focuses on the development of algorithms that allow computers to learn from and make predictions or decisions based on data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything you need to know about Java System.out.println()</title>
      <link>https://blog.ritikahotwani.com/posts/sout/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 21:57:15 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.ritikahotwani.com/posts/sout/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe statement System.out.println() is a fundamental piece of code in Java programming, often used for outputting ( printing ) information to the console.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s delve deeper into its meaning and functionality..&#xA;SyntaxSystem.out.println(argument);&#xA;The argument could be anything: a number ( integer, float, double ), a word, or a sentence.&#xA;Diving deeper into the meaningSystem :This is a predefined final class in Java&amp;rsquo;s core library (java.lang package) that provides access to system-related properties and methods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> How to create a Library Management System in Java using OOPs</title>
      <link>https://blog.ritikahotwani.com/posts/library-management-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 20:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.ritikahotwani.com/posts/library-management-system/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis blog showcases a simplistic approach to library management system implementation using Object Oriented Programming (OOP). We will be creating a library management system with the following features :&#xA;Add a new book Borrow a book Return a book Display all the books Display available books The source code of the project : github&#xA;Link of implementation : youtube&#xA;Prerequisites Java JDK installed. link to install VScode ( or any other IDE of your choice).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Java</title>
      <link>https://blog.ritikahotwani.com/posts/introduction-to-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 10:47:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.ritikahotwani.com/posts/introduction-to-java/</guid>
      <description>What is JAVAJava is a programming language and a computing platform. It is used for:&#xA;Mobile applications (Android apps) Desktop applications Web applications Web servers and application servers Games Database connection And much, much more! To it&amp;rsquo;s core, JAVA is a object-oriented programming language.&#xA;Object Oriented ProgrammingObject-oriented programming (OOP) is a programming paradigm based on the concept of objects.&#xA;Objects are nothing but the instances of classes.&#xA;A class is a blueprint for creating objects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Introduction</title>
      <link>https://blog.ritikahotwani.com/posts/personal-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 10:47:36 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.ritikahotwani.com/posts/personal-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Hola Amigos!&#xA;As I embark upon this new odyssey of sharing insights and wisdom, allow me to extend a cordial introduction and offer a glimpse into the trajectory of this blog.&#xA;About Me:I am Ritika Hotwani, a final-year student pursuing Computer Science with a minor in Data Science. My passions span a spectrum from sketching and painting to dancing and cooking, all seamlessly intertwined with my love for coding. Through this platform, I aspire to distill and share the wealth of knowledge I&amp;rsquo;ve accrued, ranging from coding exploits to navigating the complexities of placements and academic rigors.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
